Guide to the Institute of Human Relations, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Institute of Human Relations, Yale University, records
1928-1963
RU 483
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
26.25
(64 boxes)
The records consist of administrative and subject files, annual reports, financial records, publications, and correspondence documenting the activities of the Institute of Human Relations at Yale. Topics include fund-raising, special studies, associations and conferences, fellowships, and research.
Yale University. Institute of Human Relations
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 37 (YRG 37), Records of associations, institutes, centers, and organizations affiliated with Yale University.
Conditions Governing Access
The records in this collection are partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Biographical / Historical
The Institute of Human Relations (IHR) was established in 1929 at Yale University as an interdisciplinary center for cooperative research on problems of human welfare. The Institute's efforts at interdisciplinary programs to study social and cultural issues were largely funded by outside agencies. A wide range of publications and studies resulted from the Institute's projects. The administrative structure of the Institute created organizational difficulties, and the IHR was absorbed by regular departments and schools in the 1950s.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of administrative and subject files, annual reports, financial records, publications, and correspondence documenting the activities of the Institute of Human Relations at Yale. Topics include fund-raising, special studies, associations and conferences, fellowships, and research.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Anthropology -- Research; Child development; Child psychology; Human behavior; Interpersonal relations; Mental health; Research institutes; Sociology -- Research; Angell, James Rowland, 1869-1949; Bakke, E. Wight (Edward Wight), 1903-1971; Bayne-Jones, Stanhope, 1888-1970; Davie, Maurice R. (Maurice Rea), 1893-1964; Day, George Parmly, 1876-1959; Dollard, Charles, 1907-1977; Farnam, Thomas Wells, 1877-1943; Furniss, Edgar S. (Edgar Stevenson), 1890-1972; Gesell, Arnold, 1880-1961; Hiscock, Ira V. (Ira Vaughan), 1892-; Lee, Alfred McClung, 1906-; Lohmann, Carl A. (Carl Albert), 1887-; Moore, Wm. Underhill (William Underhill), 1879-1949; Nyman, Carter A.; Sapir, Edward, 1884-1939; Seymour, Charles, 1885-1963; Weigle, Luther A. (Luther Allan), 1880-1976; Winslow, C.-E. A. (Charles-Edward Amory), 1877-1957; Winternitz, M. C. (Milton C.), 1885-1959; Wissler, Clark, 1870-1947; Yerkes, Robert M. (Robert Mearns), 1876-1956; Ford Foundation; Yale University -- Buildings; Yale University -- Finance; Yale University. Child Study Center; Yale University. Institute of Human Relations
- Records, circa 1928-1963; Accession 19ND-A-159
  Conditions Governing Access
  Some financial records are restricted until January 1, 2039.
  - Annual Reports
    - 1930-1931 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1931-1932 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1932-1933 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1933-1934 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 1945-1946 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - 1952-1953 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - 1940-1948 Excerpts (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Reports to the Director, Departmental
    - 1933-1934 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 25 - 27)
    - 1935-1936 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - 1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 30 - 31)
    - 1938-1939 (Box 3, Folder 32 - 33)
    - 1939-1940 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - 1940-1941 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - 1941-1942 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - 1942-1943 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - 1943-1944 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - 1944-1945 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - 1945-1946 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - 1950-1951 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - 1951-1952 (Box 3, Folder 45 - 46)
  - Correspondence, 1928-1960
    - Ah-Al, 1941-1960 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Ame-Ami, 1936-1957 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - American Jewish Committee, 1936-1944 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - American Law Institute, 1939-1940 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - An, 1937-1957 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Angell, James Rowland, 1929-1951 (Box 5, Folder 6 - 8)
    - Angier, Roswell P., 1928-1946 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Ap-As, 1934-1958 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Applicants, 1951-1954 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Auto accident study, 1930-1939 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - At-Az, 1936-1953 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Ba-Baz, 1931-1957 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Bakke, E. Wright, 1931-1951 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Sagne-Jones, Stanhope, 1935-1939 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Be-Rez, 1936-1952 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Belcher, Ruth M., 1929-1933 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Bi-Biz, 1952-1953 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Boa-Boz, 1937-1955 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Bra-Bry, 1939-1943 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Bu -By, 1936-1951 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Ca-Caz, 1937-1941 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Cha-Chli, 1936-1946 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Child Study Center, 1941-1954 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Ci-Cl, 1935-1950 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Clinic of Child Development, 1932-1938 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Coa-Col, 1937-1939 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Com-Comz, 1933-1950 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Cra-Criz, 1935-1937 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Crank file inquiries, 1929-1931 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Da-Daz, 1935-1950 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Davie, Maurice R., 1929-1946 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Dea-Dez, 1938-1950 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Doa-Dru, 1934-1949 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Douglas, William O., 1931-1939 (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Dua-Dyz, 1937-1957 (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Ea-Em, 1939-1951 (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Emery, E. Van Norman, 1929-1940 (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - En-Ez, 1934-1952 (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Fa-Faz, 1933-1944 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - Farnam, Thomas W., 1930-1941 (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - Fe-Fez, 1936-1949 (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - Fo -Foz, 1937-1949 (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - Frank, Lawrence K., 1929-1942 (Box 8, Folder 52)
    - Ga-Gaz, 1936-1952 (Box 9, Folder 54)
    - Ge-Gez, 1933-1939 (Box 9, Folder 55)
    - Gesell, Arnold, 1930-1940 (Box 9, Folder 56)
    - Go-Goz, 1935-1940 (Box 9, Folder 57)
    - Gra-Gry, 1944-1954 (Box 9, Folder 58)
    - Har, 1936-1951 (Box 9, Folder 60)
    - Has -Haz, 1929-1953 (Box 9, Folder 61)
    - Healy, William and Bonner, Augusta, 1928-1936 (Box 9, Folder 62)
    - Hi-Hiz, 1937-1952 (Box 9, Folder 63)
    - Homburger, Erik, (Erickson), 1935-1939 (Box 9, Folder 65)
    - Human Relations Area Files, Incorporated, 1953-60 (Box 9, Folder 66)
    - Institute of Human Relations: early, 1929 (Box 10, Folder 67 - 68)
    - Ja-Jez, 1940-1942 (Box 10, Folder 69)
    - Johnson and Johnston, 1929-1940 (Box 10, Folder 70)
    - Julius Rosenwald Fund, 1940-1946 (Box 10, Folder 72)
    - Ka-Kaz, 1936-1950 (Box 10, Folder 73)
    - Kahn, Eugen, 1930-1939 (Box 10, Folder 74)
    - Ko-Ky, 1929 (Box 10, Folder 76)
    - La-Laz, 1935-1952 (Box 10, Folder 77)
    - Labor and Management Center, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 78)
    - Lee, Alfred McClung, 1938-1940 (Box 10, Folder 79)
    - Li-Llo, 1931-1942 (Box 10, Folder 80)
    - Lu-Luz, 1934-1950 (Box 11, Folder 82)
    - Lung, Harold H., 1929-1943 (Box 11, Folder 83)
    - Ma-Map, 1930-1956 (Box 11, Folder 84)
    - Macy, Josiah Jr., Foundation, 1935-1938 (Box 11, Folder 85)
    - Mar-Maz, 1931-1953 (Box 11, Folder 86)
    - Marshall, John, 1937-1943 (Box 11, Folder 87)
    - Mc, 1934-1951 (Box 11, Folder 88)
    - Mea -Mez, 1935-1937 (Box 11, Folder 89)
    - Miles, Catherine C., 1933-1942 (Box 11, Folder 90)
    - Moore, Underhill, 1930-1948 (Box 11, Folder 92)
    - Mya-Myz, 1937-1940 (Box 11, Folder 94)
    - National Committee for Mental Hygiene, 1932-1938 (Box 11, Folder 95)
    - National Conference of Christians and Jews, 1933-1944 (Box 11, Folder 96)
    - National Foundation for Education, 1941-1943 (Box 11, Folder 97)
    - National Research Council, 1935-1950 (Box 12, Folder 98 - 99)
    - National Science Foundation, 1933-1952 (Box 12, Folder 100)
    - National Youth Administration, 1935-1937 (Box 12, Folder 101)
    - Ne-Ny, 1933-1950 (Box 12, Folder 102)
    - Nyman, R. Carter, 1936-1942 (Box 12, Folder 103)
    - Oe-On, 1939-1942 (Box 12, Folder 104)
    - Ogburn, W.F., 1929-1930 (Box 12, Folder 105)
    - Op-Oz, 1936-1946 (Box 12, Folder 106)
    - Pa-Paz, 1930-1956 (Box 12, Folder 107)
    - Pe-Pez, 1934-1949 (Box 12, Folder 108)
    - Pi-Plu, 1932-1949 (Box 12, Folder 109)
    - Plans and programs, 1951-1952 (Box 12, Folder 110)
    - Pn-Poz, 1935-1949 (Box 12, Folder 111)
    - Powdermaker, Hortense, 1933-1938 (Box 12, Folder 112)
    - Pra-Pry, 1937-1952 (Box 12, Folder 113)
    - Psa-Puz, 1936-1946 (Box 12, Folder 114)
    - Psychiatry: Committee on Appointment of New Director, 1946-1947 (Box 12, Folder 115)
    - Psychological Cinema Register, 1948-1957 (Box 13, Folder 116)
    - Ra-Rap, 1935-1957 (Box 13, Folder 117)
    - Racca, Vittorio, 1929-1939 (Box 13, Folder 118)
    - Re-Rep, 1934-1947 (Box 13, Folder 119)
    - Requests A-Z, 1951-60 (Box 13, Folder 120 - 123)
    - Rha -Riz, 1933-1940 (Box 13, Folder 124)
    - Roa-Rol, 1934-1956 (Box 13, Folder 125)
    - Ron-Roz, 1933-1953 (Box 14, Folder 129)
    - Ru-Ry, 1935-1950 (Box 14, Folder 130)
    - Sa-Scu, 1929-1950 (Box 14, Folder 131)
    - Sapir, Edward, 1930-1937 (Box 14, Folder 132 - 133)
    - Sea-Sez, 1944-1950 (Box 14, Folder 134)
    - Sears, Robert R., 1936-1950 (Box 14, Folder 135)
    - Seymour, Charles, 1929-1950 (Box 14, Folder 136)
    - Sha-Shy, 1936-1939 (Box 14, Folder 137)
    - Shenton, Herbert N., 1931-1937 (Box 14, Folder 138)
    - Si-Sly, 1931-1951 (Box 14, Folder 139)
    - Slesinger, Donald, 1930-1936 (Box 14, Folder 140)
    - Sollenberger, Richard T., 1936-1937 (Box 14, Folder 142)
    - Sta-Ste, 1934-1945 (Box 14, Folder 143)
    - Su-Sy, 1931-1936 (Box 14, Folder 144)
    - Tha-Thu, 1935-1936 (Box 14, Folder 145)
    - Ti-Tiz, 1933-1939 (Box 15, Folder 147)
    - Un-Ut, 1954 (Box 15, Folder 148)
    - Vi-Vuz, 1945 (Box 15, Folder 149)
    - Visiting Fellows, 1939-1949 (Box 15, Folder 150)
    - Vocational Counseling Service, Incorporated, 1944-1951 (Box 15, Folder 151)
    - Wa-Waz, 1938 (Box 15, Folder 152)
    - Warner, Lloyd, 1934-1940 (Box 15, Folder 153)
    - Washburn, Ruth, 1936-1938 (Box 15, Folder 154)
    - We -Wez, 1933-1944 (Box 15, Folder 155)
    - Weigle, Luther A., 1928-1930 (Box 15, Folder 156)
    - Wendt, G. Richard, 1935-1936 (Box 15, Folder 157)
    - Wha- Why, 1948-1952 (Box 15, Folder 159)
    - Wi-Wil, 1929-1942 (Box 15, Folder 160)
    - Winslow, Charles-Edward A., 1931-1945 (Box 15, Folder 161)
    - Winternitz, Milton C., 1929-1937 (Box 15, Folder 162)
    - Wissler, Clark, 1929-1938 (Box 15, Folder 163)
    - Yerkes, Robert M., 1929-1958 (Box 15, Folder 164)
    - Miscellaneous, 1929-1957 (Box 16, Folder 166 - 169)
  - Subject Files, 1929-1957
    - Abstracts: Anthropology, 1930-1936 (Box 17, Folder 1 - 2)
    - Abstracts: Science and Society, 1938-1940 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Administration, 1929-1932 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Adolescence, a plan for the study of, 1933 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Adolescent research study, 1934 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Adolescent Study Unit, 1935-1940 (Box 17, Folder 7 - 9)
    - Announcements, undated (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Anxiety and Conflict: proposed book, 1941 (Box 17, Folder 12 - 13)
    - Apes: experiments, 1929-1935 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Applicants: post-doctoral, 1952 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Application blanks, undated (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Application blanks requested, 1951 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Applications rejected, 1951-1952 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Arrington, Ruth E.Time Sampling Studies of Child Behavior, 1937-1940 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Automobile driver research project:, 1936-1940 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - Bakke:Citizens Without Work and The Unemployed Worker, 1940-1951 (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - Bakke:Insurance or Dole?, 1935-1941 (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - Behavior Theoryand Social Science, 1954-1956 (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - Borchard:Convictim the Innocent, 1931-1937 (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - Bureau of Human Standards, 1929 (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - Business failures project, 1929-1934 (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - Census material, 1920-29 (Box 19, Folder 28)
    - Chart of the Institute of Human Relations, 1934-1935 (Box 19, Folder 29)
    - Child, Irvin L.:Children's Preference for Goals, undated (Box 19, Folder 30)
    - Child, Irvin L.:Italian or American?The Second Generation Conflict, 1943 (Box 19, Folder 31)
    - Child, Irvin L.: research activities, 1947 (Box 19, Folder 32)
    - Child Welfare, Committee on, 1948 (Box 19, Folder 33)
    - Claque, Couper and Bakke:After the Shutdown, 1929-1944 (Box 19, Folder 34)
    - Clippings, 1929-1931 (Box 19, Folder 35 - 37)
    - Clippings, 1929-1934 (Box 20, Folder 38 - 40)
    - College transition study, 1934-1937 (Box 20, Folder 41)
    - Conferences, Committee on, 1929-1930 (Box 20, Folder 42)
    - Contributions, memoranda on, 1949-1950 (Box 20, Folder 43)
    - Cost of Medical Care, Committee on, 1927-29 (Box 20, Folder 44)
    - Crime, Advisory Committee on: Social Science Research Council, 1930-1931 (Box 20, Folder 45)
    - Dedication excercises, 1931 (Box 20, Folder 46 - 47)
    - Dedication excercises: responses, 1931 (Box 20, Folder 48 - 49)
    - Divinity school projects, 1930 (Box 21, Folder 50)
    - Dession, George H.: disposition of criminals study, 1933 (Box 21, Folder 51)
    - Dollard, John:Caste and Class In a Southern Town, 1937 (Box 21, Folder 52)
    - Dollard, John:Criteria for the Life History, 1935-1947 (Box 21, Folder 53)
    - Dollard, John:Frustration and Aggression, 1938-1956 (Box 21, Folder 54)
    - Dollard, John: research activities, 1945 (Box 21, Folder 55)
    - Dollard and Miller:Social Learning and Imitation, 1941-1951 (Box 21, Folder 56)
    - Dollard, John and Victorine:The Strategy of Child Rearing, 1946 (Box 21, Folder 57)
    - Doob, Leonard W.:The Plans of Men, 1939-1951 (Box 21, Folder 58)
    - Dreis, Thelma A.:Handbook of Social Statistics of New Haven Connecticut, 1936-1940 (Box 21, Folder 59)
    - Dunham, Ethel C.: physical fitness study, 1935-1941 (Box 21, Folder 60)
    - "Educationally Exceptional Child", undated (Box 22, Folder 61)
    - Executive Committee, 1929-1951 (Box 22, Folder 62 - 64)
    - Experiment on persistence, undated (Box 22, Folder 65)
    - Experiment on substitute activity, undated (Box 22, Folder 66)
    - Family research, 1934 (Box 22, Folder 67)
    - Family Survey: sample correspondence, 1929-1930 (Box 22, Folder 68)
    - Fellowship Applications
      - Anthropology
        - Proposed fellowships, 1950 (Box 22, Folder 73)
      - Economics
      - History
      - Political Science
      - Psychology
      - Psychology-Behavior Theory
      - Psychology: Clinical
      - Psychology: Clinical-Social
      - Psychology: Physiological
      - Sociology
    - Ford, Cellan S.:Smoke From Their Fires, 1941 (Box 25, Folder 137)
    - Frustration, aggression: memoranda on, 1936-1937 (Box 25, Folder 138)
    - Healy and Bonner: delinquency study, 1930 (Box 26, Folder 139 - 140)
    - Healy and Bonner: Detroit Clinic, 1923-1932 (Box 26, Folder 141)
    - Healy and Bonner:New Light on Delinquency and Its Treatment, 1936-1958 (Box 26, Folder 142)
    - Heermance project, 1929-1932 (Box 26, Folder 143)
    - House bulletin suggestion regarding research work, 1933 (Box 26, Folder 144)
    - Hovland, Carl:Order of Presentation in Persuasion, 1957 (Box 26, Folder 145)
    - Hull, Clark L.:A Mathematico-Deductive Theory of Rote Learning, 1939-1942 (Box 26, Folder 146)
    - Hull, Clark L.:Essentials of Behavior, 1951 (Box 26, Folder 147)
    - Hull, Clark: Psychology 106, Prinicipals of Learning, 1939-1941 (Box 26, Folder 148)
    - Hull, Clark: research memoranda, 1934-1945 (Box 26, Folder 149)
    - Human Biology and Ecology, 1951-1952 (Box 27, Folder 150)
    - Human Relations to Relief Study, 1935 (Box 27, Folder 151 - 152)
    - Human Relations in Industry: reports, 1930-1934 (Box 27, Folder 153)
    - Human Welfare Group
      - Book Information, undated (Box 27, Folder 154)
      - Bulletins I-VIII, 1930 (Box 27, Folder 155)
      - Current memoranda, 1931 (Box 27, Folder 156)
      - Dentistry: proposed development, 1931 (Box 27, Folder 157)
      - Fellows of the institute, 1930 (Box 27, Folder 158)
      - Financial needs, 1929, 1931, 1936 (Box 27, Folder 159)
      - "For Better Understanding of Human Behavior": Statement bv M. Schoolcraft, used by George Day, 1936 (Box 27, Folder 160)
      - Macy, Josiah Jr., Foundation, 1930 (Box 27, Folder 161)
      - National Advisory Committee, 1929-1931 (Box 28, Folder 162 - 164)
      - Project pending, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 165)
      - Speeches at Waterbury dinner, 1929 (Box 28, Folder 166)
      - Summary of purpose and plan, 1931 (Box 28, Folder 167)
      - The Alice Kimball English Pavilion, 1928 (Box 28, Folder 168)
    - Institute: Special Studies
      - Anthropology, 1931-1934 (Box 28, Folder 169)
      - Bankruptcy, 1929 (Box 28, Folder 170)
      - Delinquency, 1929 (Box 28, Folder 172)
      - Lecture series: Social aspects of medicine, 1935 (Box 28, Folder 173)
      - Neurological Study Unit, 1933 (Box 28, Folder 174)
      - Psychology, 1922-28 (Box 29, Folder 175 - 176)
      - Religion, 1931 (Box 29, Folder 177)
      - Work relief project, 1932 (Box 29, Folder 178)
    - Interviews: held formally with M.A. May, 1935-1941 (Box 29, Folder 179)
    - Japanese Character Structure, 1942 (Box 29, Folder 180)
    - Laws and Theory for Social Scientist: Logan, Frank A., undated (Box 29, Folder 181)
    - Lectures requested, 1935 (Box 29, Folder 182)
    - Legal control memoranda: Moore, Underhill, 1934 (Box 29, Folder 183)
    - Mahl, George F.: research activities, 1947-1949 (Box 29, Folder 184)
    - May, Mark A.:A Social Psychology of War and Peace, 1942-1951 (Box 29, Folder 185)
    - May, Mark A.:Toward A Science of Human Behavior, 1949-1952 (Box 29, Folder 186)
    - Medical research: clippings, 1931-1932 (Box 30, Folder 187)
    - Memoranda: general, 1934-1937 (Box 30, Folder 188)
    - Mental Hygiene, 1930-1932 (Box 30, Folder 189 - 190)
    - Mental Hygiene and Education, Committee on, 1933 (Box 30, Folder 191)
    - Mental Hygiene: college students, 1930-1931 (Box 30, Folder 192 - 193)
    - Mental Hygiene Community Service, 1937 (Box 30, Folder 194)
    - Methology in Social Science Thomas, D., 1930 (Box 30, Folder 195)
    - Migration Studies, undated (Box 30, Folder 196)
    - Migration Studies: Thomas, Dorothy Swain, 1929 (Box 30, Folder 197)
    - Miscellaneous: memoranda, notes, outlines, 1929-1933 (Box 30, Folder 201)
    - Monday' Night Group
      - 1939-1940 (Box 30, Folder 202)
      - 1940-1941 (Box 31, Folder 203 - 204)
      - 1941-1942 (Box 31, Folder 205)
      - 1942-1943 (Box 31, Folder 206)
      - 1943-1944 (Box 31, Folder 207)
      - 1946-1947 (Box 31, Folder 208)
      - 1949-1950 (Box 31, Folder 209)
      - Abstract of sessions, 1938-1939 (Box 31, Folder 210)
      - A Demonstration of Anti-dating Total Goal Reactions: Hull, C.L., undated (Box 31, Folder 211)
      - A Review of Some Behavior Mechanisms: Hull, C.L., undated (Box 31, Folder 212)
      - Goal Reactions as Pure Stimulus Acts: Hull, C.L., undated (Box 31, Folder 213)
      - Invention and Diffusion in Culture: Linton, R., 1939 (Box 31, Folder 214)
      - Papers presented, 1939-1940 (Box 31, Folder 215 - 216)
      - Some Hypotheses on the Learning of Language by Children: Bollard and Miller, undated (Box 32, Folder 217)
      - Symbolic Logic and Scientific Language: Fitch, F.B., undated (Box 32, Folder 218)
      - The Approximation of Subhuman Organisms to True Cooperative and Language Behavior: Hull, C.L., undated (Box 32, Folder 219)
      - The Freudian Theories of Anxiety: A Reconciliation: Mower, O.H., undated (Box 32, Folder 220)
      - The Function and Structure of Language: Bloomfield, L., undated (Box 32, Folder 221)
      - The Origin and Evolution of Trade Unions: Bakke, E.W., 1940-1941 (Box 32, Folder 222)
      - The Use of Language in Teaching at Kowoma: Whiting, J.W., undated (Box 32, Folder 223)
      - Theories of Signs: Gorer, G., undated (Box 32, Folder 224)
      - Words and Their Contexts as Stimulus Aggregates in Action Evocation: Hull, C.L., undated (Box 32, Folder 225)
      - Words as Cues for Specific Responses: Miller, N.E., undated (Box 32, Folder 226)
    - Motor Vehical Accidents I, II, III, 1930-1934 (Box 32, Folder 227 - 229)
    - Motor Vehical Accidents, Committee on, 1931-1932 (Box 32, Folder 230)
    - Mower, O.H.:Preparatory Set(Expectancy), 1940 (Box 32, Folder 231)
    - News releases, 1929-1932 (Box 33, Folder 232 - 233)
    - Nutritution and Increments of Growth study, 1934 (Box 33, Folder 234)
    - Nyman, R.C.:Union Management Cooperation in the Stretch Out, 1934-1954 (Box 33, Folder 235)
    - National Advisory Committee, 1929 (Box 33, Folder 236)
    - Organizational plans, 1930-1936 (Box 33, Folder 237)
    - Personnel, Committee on, 1929-1930 (Box 33, Folder 238)
    - Personnel research, 1937 (Box 33, Folder 239)
    - Pittsburg dinner: invitations, 1930 (Box 33, Folder 240)
    - Post-doctoral Fellows meetings, 1951 October 9-16 (Box 33, Folder 241 - 246)
    - Post-doctoral Fellows meetings, 1951 October 17-1952 February 18 (Box 34, Folder 247 - 253)
    - Post-doctoral Pellows in Behavior Science: appointments, 1952-1954 (Box 34, Folder 254)
    - Post-doctoral Fellows: recording discs, 1951 (Box 34, Folder 255)
    - Powdermaker, Hortense, 1938 (Box 34, Folder 256)
    - Prenatal Care, Report of the Evaluation of: Tyler, Watkins and Walker, 1934-1935 (Box 34, Folder 257)
    - Pre-school study, 1937-1938 (Box 34, Folder 258)
    - Projects proposed, 1929-1951 (Box 34, Folder 259)
    - Psychiatry Department, 1935-1937 (Box 34, Folder 260 - 261)
    - Psychoanalysis: memoranda, 1930 (Box 34, Folder 262)
    - Psychology: criminal, 1931 (Box 35, Folder 263)
    - Psychology and law, undated (Box 35, Folder 264)
    - Publications
      - Bibliographical material, 1931-1937 (Box 35, Folder 265 - 266)
      - Contracts with Yale University Press, 1931-1953 (Box 35, Folder 267)
      - Correspondence: miscellaneous, 1929-1933 (Box 35, Folder 268 - 272)
      - Correspondence, miscellaneous, 1934-1940 (Box 36, Folder 273 - 274)
      - General, 1931-1957 (Box 36, Folder 275 - 276)
      - Lists, 1939-1951 (Box 36, Folder 277)
      - Psychiatry and Mental Hygiene, Department of, 1929-1939 (Box 36, Folder 278)
      - Report of sales, 1935-1954 (Box 36, Folder 279 - 280)
      - Reprints, 1931-1940 (Box 36, Folder 281)
    - Publicity, 1929-1937 (Box 36, Folder 282)
    - Publicity, 1929-1939 (Box 37, Folder 283 - 286)
    - Questions and Answers: booklet, 1929 (Box 37, Folder 287)
    - Racca, Vittorio: a few selected family histories of Italians living in New Haven, undated (Box 37, Folder 288)
    - Requests for institute funds granted, 1931-1934 (Box 37, Folder 289)
    - Requests for institute funds rejected, 1929-1938 (Box 37, Folder 290)
    - Research Conference on Social Classes: synopsis, 1939 (Box 38, Folder 291)